Akane, can you hear me?
茜，听得到我说话吗？
I'm going to pick you up.
我要抱你起来了
ORIGINAL STORY BY MASHIRO
（原作：Mashiro）
Has he answered?
有接吗？
No.
没接
Maybe his tutoring lesson has taken longer than he thought.
大概是家教打工拖久了吧
Even so, it's rare for him not to leave a message.
就算如此，毫无联络真是少见
You never know, maybe he's with a woman.
说不定他其实在跟女生玩
That phone call from before was pretty suspicious too.
上次那通电话也很可疑
Yamada-kun's not the type.
山田同学不是那种个性的人吧
You don't get it, Ms. President.
班长，你真是不懂耶
If you don't get serious,
你再这么悠哉
another woman will pop up one day and snatch him from you.
小心他被半路杀出的女人抢走哦
I know that.
我也知道
I know, okay?
我当然知道
Don't try to frighten me.
不用威胁我
If it bothers you that much,
既然你用情那么深
why don't you just tell him?
为什么不早点告白啊？
What's stopping you?
不懂你在别扭什么
One day, he'll meet someone.
自己总有一天会遇见某人
I have that feeling.
我一直这么认为
Yamada-kun, you know GOS:E, don't you?
山田同学 你知道“GOS:E”吗？
It's an FPS game.
是FPS的游戏
You play it, right?
你有在玩吧？
You had a match with me yesterday, at 10 p.m.
昨晚十点左右，我们有在线上对战
Do you remember?
有印象吗？
I'm Yukari Tsubaki from Class D.
我是D班的椿由香里
I went by the name "YT03" when I battled you.
昨天用“YT03” 这个名字和你对战
If you don't mind,
你不介意的话
I'd like you to demonstrate how you play.
我想看你对战时的操作过程
I DON'T REMEMBER AT ALL…
（我根本不记得…）
Why?
为什么？
I'm wondering about a few things.
因为我有点好奇
She thinks you're cheating.
人家在怀疑你用外挂
Once you see it, please leave.
看完就要马上走哦
Of course.
当然
Tsubaki,
小椿
make sure to watch my dazzling play later too.
晚点也看看我的华丽对战吧
To be honest, I was suspicious.
我原本确实有点怀疑你
I didn't believe anyone could play like that on skill alone.
想说怎么可能只靠实力强成那样
I'm sorry.
对不起
It was my own ignorance.
是我太无知了
Talented people exist.
原来有这么厉害的人
Have you thought about turning pro?
你可以当职业玩家吧？
Just like I met him…
就像我遇见了你一样
one day…
你总有一天
he'll meet someone.
也会遇见某人
For someone whose looks draw so much attention,
虽然有一张万人迷的脸
he's quiet and reserved.
个性却是寡言低调
Despite the emotionless way he talks,
讲话看似冷漠
he's thought of as pretty kind.
态度其实蛮亲切的
The people who are closest to him
和他有交情的人
know all that well.
都知道他的为人
But they also know…
还有…
Yamada-kun,
山田同学
we were at the same committee meeting last week.
我上星期有和你参加干部会议
You were a big help and…
你帮了我很多忙…
I wanted…
而且…
Have we spoken before?
我们有说过话吗？
He can be a bit cruel.
也知道他偶尔有点残酷
Hey, did you hear?
你听说了吗？
Shiraishi from Class B
D班的白石同学
finally asked Yamada out.
终于向山田同学告白了
For real?
真的假的？
But he shot her down.
但一样也败阵了
If Shiraishi isn't good enough for him, who is?
连白石同学都被拒绝，谁能成功啊？
Maybe he's not into women.
说不定他不喜欢女生
Seriously? What a waste!
是那一挂？讨厌，太可惜了
MATHEMATICS
（有点同情他）
2-B CLASS DIARY, SECOND SEMESTER
（学级日志 第二学期）
CLASS REPS FOR THE DAY
（值日生）
As popular as you are, if you remain single,
这么受欢迎，却一直单身
people will start to gossip.
小心被乱传八卦哦
NO RESPONSE
（厌烦）
Does it really matter what people think?
别人怎么说都没差吧
That's true,
虽然是这样
but I feel bad hearing people say as they please about you.
看你被说三道四，感觉很可怜
Do you at least have a type?
你没有喜欢的类型吗？
Not really.
没什么
You must have some sort of preference.
应该还是有什么条件吧
None.
没有
Seriously? Then, what about a first love--
那你有过初恋吗？
I really…
我已经说了…
don't.
真的没有
He sighed!
他叹气了
-Forgive me… -No, I'm sorry.
-不好意思 -不会，抱歉
I've been pestering you.
是我太缠人了
OOPS…
（沮丧…）
Better learn my lesson.
我要反省
Um…
那个…
So then…
就是…那个…
Now that you mention it…
这么说起来
Huh?
（丧气）
A long time ago, there was a girl who had a crush on me.
以前有个女生说喜欢我
She was bullied badly…
那女生在学校被霸凌得很惨
BUILLIED?
（霸凌？）
…and stopped coming to school most days.
她后来几乎没来上学
Her house was near mine,
因为我们住得近
so our teacher asked me to deliver things to her
班导常请我送东西过去
and we became friends before long.
于是我们就熟了起来
But even on days when she did come to school,
不过，她偶尔来上学时
she felt lost if I wasn't there
好像没有我，就会无所适从
and I tried to stay by her side at all times.
所以我就尽量陪着她
So then,
那么…
you liked her, right?
山田同学那时也喜欢她啊
Akito…
秋斗
will you stay with me forever,
就算长大了
even when we're adults?
我们也要永远在一起哦
How could I know that?
那种事…我无法保证啊
I was just doing
我只是因为…
what our teacher
班导叫我这么做
told me to do.
才会陪着她
The bullying never stopped,
结果她还是持续遭到霸凌
and she eventually transferred.
最后转学了
But sometimes I think back…
但我偶尔会想起她的事
The last time we spoke,
我们最后说话时
I made her cry badly,
我害她哭得好凶
and I wonder what the correct thing
我偶尔会思考怎么回答
would've been to say.
才是正确答案
I couldn't understand
因为一直搞不懂
and somehow, it got to be a pain.
我开始…觉得很烦
Ever since then,
从那之后
girls make me really uncomfortable.
我就很不擅长应付女生
So that's it.
这样啊
He has no interest in himself.
这个人对自己没什么兴趣啊
So even when people have feelings for him,
所以遇到对自己有好感的人
he can't see it.
他也不会好好正视
Or maybe he tries not to.
又或者是故意不去面对
"It got to be a pain"?
他说觉得很烦
Talk about scary.
真恐怖
I can't let myself fall in love with him.
我必须要小心别喜欢上他
CLASS REPS AKITO YAMADA, YUKARI TSUBAKI
（值日生 山田秋斗 椿由香里）
If I fall in love with a guy this cruel,
要是喜欢上这么残酷的人
I'm sure to get hurt.
有一天一定会受伤
I don't want that.
我讨厌这样
COOLING PADS
（退热贴）
GASP
（喘气）
Delivery… delivery…
外卖…
Akane, can you drink this water?
茜，你喝得下水吗？
I can't…
没办法…
Even if it's tough, you should drink a little.
就算如此，你还是要喝点水
BLURGH
（猛吐）
THAT DIDN'T WORK…
（还是不行啊… 猛吐）
You're burning up.
脸好烫
This fever could be serious.
烧成这样，不太妙吧？
I'm… cold…
好…好冷
It hurts…
好难受
I feel hot…
好热…
and cold…
好冷…
What's going on?
怎么回事？
Something's spinning
在眼睛的深处
at the edge of my vision.
世界在旋转
What's…
我现在…
happening to me?
变得怎么样了？
Akane…
茜…
Akane!
茜
Where's your health insurance card?
你的健保卡在哪里？
Your insurance card…
健保卡
In… my purse…
在包包…里面…
Huh?
奇怪？
Just now,
我刚才…
it felt like Yamada was here.
好像看到山田了
It must be my imagination.
是我的错觉吧
EVENING OUTPATIENT WARD
（夜间门诊）
Ms. Kinoshita?
木之下小姐
Can you hear me?
有听到吗？
Yes…
有…
-But why…? -I'm going to give you an IV.
-不过话说回来 -现在帮你打点滴哦
-Why is it so noisy? -Let me roll up your sleeve.
-感觉好吵闹哦 -我要卷袖子了哦
Huh?
奇怪？
What time…
现在…
is it?
几点了？
Did I fall asleep?
我在那之后睡着了？
In the end…
结果…
I couldn't make it to the store.
还是没去买东西
But somehow…
不过感觉上
I feel a little better.
身体好像好多了
Wh…
为…
Why?
为什么？
It's cold.
好冷
What are you doing here?
为什么你会在这里？
VENTILATING
（换气中）
WHAT?!
（什么？）
I know. It must be a dream!
这样啊，是做梦
So cold…
好冷
SHE SURE SNEEZES VIOLENTLY…
（打喷嚏的方式真怪…）
You can stand now, I see.
你已经可以站起来了啊
How do you feel?
现在感觉如何？
Surprised.
我觉得很惊讶
That's not what I meant.
我不是在问这个
This isn't a dream? Why are you here?
这不是做梦吗？为什么你在这？
I don't want you to catch my cold!
话说传染给你就糟了
It hurts!
头好痛
I'll explain properly,
我会好好说明
so please get back in bed.
你先躺下来比较好
You couldn't even drink.
你原本连水也喝不下
It was a dangerous situation.
还蛮严重的
Yeah…
好…
And so…
然后
How are you feeling?
现在感觉如何？
Well…
这么说起来
when I woke up, it felt like
刚才起来的时候
I had gotten a little better.
好像觉得好多了
I WONDER WHY…
（是为什么啊？）
Glad to hear it.
那就好
I came to check and found you
我来看状况之后
collapsed near your bicycle.
发现你倒在自行车停放处
Really?!
是那样吗？
Now that you mention it.
说起来
-For a split-second. -You'd better get back inside.
-我的确好像在一瞬间 -所以我就先把你移到房间
I did think I saw him.
看到像山田的人
So then, he really did come to my aid.
所以真的是山田救了我
You were in pretty bad shape.
因为你看起来很难受
He was worried
他是因为担心我
and came to check on me?
才跑来关心我的状况吗？
Was he here all night,
明明有可能会被传染
even though he could catch my cold?
他还是一直陪着我吗？
STUNNED…
（感动）
-Why is he so kind? -I found a hospital with evening care.
-他为什么这么体贴？ -我找了夜间有看诊的医院
-Just for my sake? -And you saw a doctor.
-为了我这种人 -带你过去看病
Huh?
什么？
I'm really happy.
我好高兴
Thank you, Yamada.
山田，谢谢你了
It was awful being alone like this.
一个人真的好不舒服
You saved my life!
你是我的救命恩人
I don't know how to thank you!
我该怎么回报这份恩情才好？
You're an angel!
你是天使
Uh, right.
啊，是哦
GIDDY FROM HER FEAVER
（因为高烧 情绪激动）
Anyway, if I can continue…
然后关于之后的事…
I'm so sorry for ever saying
你明明这么贴心
that you act cold!
我却说你冷漠，真是抱歉
Did she say that to me?
她有这么说过吗？
From the beginning, you've always been kind!
山田从一开始就好温柔
If you keep moving, you'll fall.
你再乱动，会摔下床的
Excuse me, I stepped on your book.
抱歉，我踩到了
Hey wait, that's…
奇怪，那本书…
FOR ALL THOSE WITH BROKEN HEARTS
（《献给失恋的你》）
I had time on my hands, so I took the liberty of reading it.
因为很闲，我就擅自借来看了
It's a good book, right?
是本好书吧？
It really helped me a lot.
我被这本书拯救了好多次
I didn't quite get it.
我其实看不太懂
It's not written for people like you.
这是和你无关的书啦
You're the type
真要算的话
who rejects more than they're rejected.
你应该是常甩人的那一方
That's not--
没那回事
There you go again…
少来了
You're acting kind of scary.
你的情绪从刚才就很激动
Oh, the pain…
头好痛…
Well, I'm sure having to reject people is tough too.
但我想甩人的那方也很难受啦
Especially for someone kind like you.
像山田特别温柔，一定很痛苦吧
I…
其实…
I'm not… that nice a guy.
我这个人…没你想得那么好
Takuma had the same expression.
拓马也是那样的表情
In pain from guilt or something…
看上去一脸歉意，感觉很难受
He looked like he wanted to disappear.
很想消失的表情
Don't worry about it so much. It's love.
有什么关系，毕竟是谈恋爱嘛
That's how it is.
本来就是这样
Even though he cheated?
明明是你被劈腿？
Well…
也是啦
Now that some time has passed,
但现在仔细想想
I feel kind of grateful that he broke it off cleanly, rather than lie.
幸好他有老实说出来，直接甩掉我
I'm sorry, Akane.
茜，抱歉
Thanks to that, I avoided the worst.
我才不至于遇到真正悲惨的事
Forgive me.
抱歉…
I knew I couldn't change his mind,
我知道怎样都挽回不了
so I accepted the breakup, right away.
所以立刻就同意分手了
I understand.
我明白了
Besides,
以后有一天
one day, this will all be a nostalgic memory
当他回想起这一段恋情时
and rather than crying in despair,
比起哇哇大哭的我
I'd rather him remember me smiling.
希望他能想起的是我的笑容
I want him to think, "She was a good woman."
让他感叹我有多么好
"I shouldn't have let her get away."
懊悔自己竟然甩了我
Wouldn't that be better?
这种结局好多了吧？
You… felt sorry for me?
你在可怜我吗？
Goodbye, Akito.
再见了，秋斗
I'm sorry!
对不起
Thank you for always being there for me!
谢谢你一直陪着我
Goodbye!
再见了
Yeah.
的确是这样
OFFLINE MEMBERS YAMADA
（离线：山田）
Is your fever down?
退烧了吗？
I think so.
退得差不多了
I DON'T KNOW HOW HIGH IT WAS, THOUGH…
（虽然不知道严重时是几度…）
Mind if I eat the yogurt you bought me?
我可以吃你买来的优格吗？
Go ahead.
请吃吧
MUNCH MUCH SNIFFLE SNIFFLE
（啜泣…咀嚼…）
It's so good, you're in tears?
好吃到哭出来吗？
Swallowing is really painful.
吞下去的时候爆痛
If it had been a man other than Yamada here,
如果待在这里的男人不是山田
I probably would have panicked.
我肯定会很慌张吧
What is it about him
该怎么说？
that makes me feel so safe and secure?
山田这股安心又安全的氛围
I SEE ANGEL WINGS…
（背后好像有天使翅膀…）
Then again, it only brings him trouble.
但对他来说是一场恶梦吧
It just adds to his discomfort with girls.
毕竟他本来就不擅长应付女性了
Thank you for the meal.
谢谢招待
Could you put this over there?
可以帮我放到那里吗？
Sure.
好的
Oh, no…
糟糕
My leg…
我的脚…
I think it's gonna cramp…
好像快抽筋…
It's cramping. Ow…
在抽筋了，好痛…
-Th… that… -You should stretch--
你把脚伸直
Oh my god, that hurts!
好痛！
You'd better stretch it.
必须伸直才行
AGONY
（痛到昏倒）
All right…
真是的
Akane!
茜
Please extend your leg.
脚…借我一下
Ow!
痛死了！
No way! It's too painful!
不行…痛…
Don't touch it!
痛死了！不要碰
Quiet down.
你安静点
Just a little longer.
忍耐一下
Oh, that hurts! It hurts! It…
痛…
feels better.
开始不痛了
Right?
对吧？
I thought I was gonna die.
我还以为会挂掉
You're exagg--
太夸张了吧
It really did hurt.
因为真的很痛啊
Huh?
奇怪？
Somehow, it's almost as if he's staring at me.
他好像猛盯着我看…
Wait…
怪了？
Why did I think he…
我为什么会觉得
was safe?
他让人放心？
HIT HER HEAD
（刺痛 撞到头了）
What? I didn't dodge, I swear!
什么？我没在躲你哦
What? Why are you laughing?
什么？为什么要笑？
No reason.
没什么
What's there to laugh about?!
为什么要笑啦？
You've got it wrong! Really!
就说没躲了，真的没有
You've got it wrong!
真的没在躲你
I'll be going, then.
那我回去了
You're going to school on no sleep?
你都没睡，就这样去上学？
Yes. I'm used to it.
是的，我习惯了
I'm really sorry.
真的很抱歉
If you start feeling bad, tell me.
要是不舒服，记得跟我说
And thank you for the hospital and everything else.
还有医院的事，谢谢你帮了那么多
I'll do something to pay you back soon.
下次我会好好回礼的
I didn't do anything major.
不是什么大不了的事
Please don't worry about it.
你不用放在心上
They said to return in the afternoon
医院说你先观察一天
after a day had passed.
之后白天再去看诊一次
If you could, do that please.
后续就麻烦你了
It should be okay.
嗯，没问题
IT WAS ENDO HOSPITAL, RIGHT?
（是远藤医院没错吧？）
They said that at night,
在夜间时段
they can't do a detailed examination.
果然无法做太精细的检查
But then, you got better from the IV,
吊完点滴虽然恢复得不错
so it's probably just a precaution.
还是去一趟比较保险
Anyway, sorry for the intrusion.
那我失陪了
Excuse me…
对不起
I didn't know you were that close.
我没想到你靠得这么近
No, I'm sorry. I stood too close.
抱歉，是我靠太近了
My body
我的身体…
almost seemed to be moving on its own.
好像自动被吸过去了一样
Akane… I have to go.
茜，我必须走了
Oh, s… sorry! It's nothing! Go on!
对…对不起，没什么，你走吧
Will you be okay?
-你没事吧？ -我没事！你快走！
Oh, I know!
对了
After I visit the clinic, I can tell you how it went.
等我看完医生，再跟你报告结果吧
I'm sure it's just an ordinary cold.
虽然八成只是普通感冒
Oh, is it unnecessary?
抱歉，也不用向你报告吧
It m… might already have spread to you.
因…因为我怕不小心传染给你
I thought maybe you were worried.
觉得你应该会在意啦
That's all!
只是这样而已
In that case…
那么…
-Please do. -Right!
-再麻烦你了 -好的
Take care.
请保重